《絕命律師》前請提要
Previously, on "Better Call Saul."
前兩晚  我聽到了槍聲
Last two nights, I heard gun shots.
那你和凱莉要離開這棟房子
We're getting you and Kaylee out of this house.
五萬塊  槍是你的
50,000 and the gun is yours.
如果你碰巧正在尋求改變
If you're pondering a change,
斯韋卡特考科利會很樂意
Schweikart and Coakley would be more than happy
善用你的才華
to put your talents to good use.
我對哈姆林麥吉爾聯合律所沒有怨言
I have no complaints about HHM.
你進戴維斯梅因律所是為了我
You took the Davis and Main job because of me.
我去那里工作是因為這是正確的決定
I took that job because it was the right decision.
我得到了我想要的
I got what I wanted.
你可以得到你想要的一切
You could have everything you ever wanted.
還有什么不滿意的
What's not to love about that?
What's not to love?
《瘋狂》雜志
《花花公子》
十八禁
吉米  掃地掃得怎么樣了
Jimmy, how's that sweepin' going?
掃著呢  老爸
Goin' good, pop.
你好嗎
Hi. How are ya?
你好  先生
Hello, sir.
不知道你能不能幫我個忙
Uh, I was wondering if maybe you could help me.
什么事
Yeah?
我今早開車進城
Well, I drove into the city this morning.
通常我都搭火車  但今天特別趕時間
U-usually, I take the train, but I was in just such a rush
趕著給我兒子弗萊迪買藥
to get some medicine for my son, Freddie.
他有癲癇
He has epilepsy.
今天早上發作的時候
He had an attack this morning, but during his fit,
打翻了我妻子手中的藥
he knocked the bottle of medicine out of my wife's hand
砰一聲  撒了一地
and just -- bam, one huge puddle.
真糟糕
That's terrible.
長話短說吧  我開車進城
Well, long story short -- drove into town,
身上所有錢都拿去買了藥
bought the new medicine with every last nickel in my pocket,
接著我的車就拋錨了
and then my car died.
我的天  這實在...
Oh, god, that's -- that's just, uh...
我知道
I know.
屋漏偏逢連夜雨  對吧
When it rains, it pours, right?
我試著發動  怎么也點不著
I-I tried the ignition, just nothin' -- not firing.
總之  我只知道
And, anyway, now I've convinced myself
在我帶藥回家之前
that Freddie's ‭gonna have another seizure
弗萊迪的癲癇隨時會再次發作
before I get back with the medicine.
要是你能幫我  我會感激不盡
So, i-if you can help me, I would be so grateful.
我可以幫你檢查一下車子
Well, I could come out and check your car for ya.
可能只是火花塞的問題
You know, ‭maybe it's just a spark plug.
我儲藏室里有一盒火花塞
I-I-I got a box of plugs back in the stockroom.
謝謝  我很感激
Thanks, ‭and I-I appreciate that,
但如果你能給我五塊就好了...
but if you could possibly just spare $5 instead...
我寧可打車也不愿再折騰我那破車
I'd rather grab a cab than take a chance with my old clunker.
好啊  五元
Yeah, $5.
如果能給的話
I-if you can spare it.
行  當然
Yeah, okay, sure.
爸  過來一下
Dad, c'mere!
過來一下
C'mere!
爸  這是詐騙  跟上周那個乞丐一樣
Dad, it's a rip-off, just like that bum from last week.
吉米
Jimmy.
鎮上的騙棍都知道
Every grifter in town knows that
這里是騙取施舍的好地點
this is the spot to come for an easy handout.
"騙棍"  你哪里學來的詞
Grifter? Where in the world did you learn that word?
爸  他鬼話連篇
Dad, his story's baloney.
他多半根本沒有兒子
He probably doesn't even have a son.
他在敲詐你
He's conning you.
吉米  萬一你錯了呢
Jimmy... What if you're wrong?
這樣吧
Y-you know what?
很抱歉麻煩你們  我這就走
Sorry to bother you folks. I-I'm gonna get outta here.
-我這就...  -不不不
- I-I'm gonna... - No, no, no, no, no.
-爸  -不  不麻煩
- Dad. - ‭No, no bother.
來吧  這兒
Come on. Now, here.
給你十元吧
There's $10 for you.
先生  你...
Sir, y-you're --
真的很慷慨
That's -- that is so generous.
沒事  這樣吧
Of course, and -- and you know what?
我去后面儲藏室
I'm gonna go back in the stockroom.
找點火花塞
I'm gonna find those spark plugs.
或許能幫你把車發動  如何
Maybe we'll get your car started for you, okay?
來吧  吉米  幫我看一會兒行嗎
Come on, Jimmy. Just man the till, okay?
我馬上回來
And I'll just be back in a jiff, okay?
一條酷爾煙多少錢
How much for a carton of Kools?
四塊錢
4 bucks.
好  來一條
Yeah, gimme a carton.
先付錢
Money first.
來兩條吧
Gimme two cartons.
天啊
Oh, gosh.
火花塞分明就在這里
These spark plugs are back here somewhere.
再給我一分鐘好嗎
Just give me one more minute, okay?
快點吧
Come on.
這世上有兩類人  狼和羊  孩子
There are wolves and sheep in this world, kid.
狼和羊
Wolves and sheep --
想清楚你要成為哪一種
Figure out ‭which one you're gonna be.
等等
Wait. Just...Just...
好啦  找到了
Okay, I-I found the, um...
他走了嗎
Did he leave?
他剛走嗎
Oh, did he just leave?
先生
Sir!
絕命律師
第二季 第七集
原創翻譯  雙語字幕
翻譯  TheWalkingNerd  喵球球  肉松
翻譯  joy_bwl  酸奶  西陵折枝 杏仁
校對  喃喃
別讓我打擾你
Don't let me interrupt.
抱歉  準備好了嗎
Sorry. You ready?
走吧  趕緊把這事解決了
Hey, come on. Let's get this over with.
時間軸   姜姜  夢龍
感謝您抽空見我們
Thank you for seeing us.
我們不想耽誤太久
We don't wanna take up too much of your time,
后期 daylight小新  總監  喃喃
我就開門見山吧
so I'll get right to it.
很遺憾地告訴你們  經過事后回憶
Um, I regret to inform you that with the benefit of hindsight,
打開微信   掃描左側二維碼
或搜索公眾號:    美劇炸了
了解最新影視資訊字幕信息
厄門紹特先生決定小小地修改一下陳述
Mr. Ehrmantraut will be amending his original statement a tad.
-小小地  -一點點
- A tad? ‭- A wee bit.
他決定不能再昧著良心
He's decided that he can no longer in good conscience claim
說現場發現的槍是屠庫·塞拉曼加的
claim that the gun found at the scene belonged to Tuco Salamanca.
-那是誰的槍呢  -誰知道呢
- So, whose gun was it? ‭- Who's to say?
你知道阿爾布開克有多少槍嗎
You know how many guns there are in Albuquerque?
少如響尾蛇  多則如沙粒
Somewhere between the number of rattlesnakes and grains of sand.
所以很多
So...a lot.
是你的槍嗎  厄門紹特先生
Was it your gun, Mr. Ehrmantraut?
他沒這么說
No, he's not saying that.
能讓厄門紹特先生自己說嗎
Can we hear it from Mr. Ehrmantraut?
槍不是塞拉曼加的
The gun wasn't Salamanca's.
我只知道這么多
That's all I can tell you.
你原來說是他的
You told us it was.
你說塞拉曼加掏出槍對著你
You said Salamanca pulled it and pointed it at you.
他沒有
Well, he didn't.
-你為什么要改陳述  -好公民嘛
- Why are you changing your story? ‭- Good citizenship.
槍上只有一個人的指紋
Look, there was only one set of prints on the gun --
塞拉曼加的
Salamanca's.
槍怎么可能不是他的呢
How's that gonna happen if it wasn't his?
這個就不能問我的委托人了  對吧
That's not really for my client to say, now, is it?
他又不是鑒定專家
He's not a forensics expert.
誰知道呢  說不定
Who knows? Maybe it, uh,
是從飛過的鳥兒嘴里掉下來的
fell ‭from a passing bird's beak,
塞拉曼加先生接住了槍想扔掉
and Mr. Salamanca caught it and tried to throw it away.
我是說有好多可能性
I mean, ‭the possibilities are endless.
塞拉曼加威脅你了嗎  厄門紹特先生
Did Salamanca threaten you, Mr. Ehrmantraut?
我們想讓他多關幾年
We wanna put this guy away for years.
槍是最關鍵的  你們知道
The gun makes all the difference. You know that.
你想讓他早點出來再次傷害你嗎
You gonna let this person victimize you twice?
別說槍的事了  行嗎
Forget about the gun, all right?
槍不是塞拉曼加的
The gun was not Salamanca's.
如果你們要把槍納為證據
If you try to introduce it into evidence,
厄門紹特先生會幫被告人辯護
Mr. Ehrmantraut ‭will make himself available to the defense,
他會澄清是非
and he will set the record straight,
直截了當  毫不含糊
categorically and unequivocally.
他威脅你了  還是賄賂你了
Did he threaten you or pay you off?
夠了  到此為止  走吧
Okay, that's it. We're done. Okay. Let's go.
你沒做錯
You're doing the right the thing.
這個叫塞拉曼加的
This Salamanca character?
簡直是瘋子
Maniac.
我自己也
I had my own...
跟他打過交道
...thing with him.
之前因為利益沖突啊啥的  就沒有說
I didn't wanna say it before because of conflict of interest,
但是他確實是個神經病
yadda yadda, but, yeah, he's nuts.
他把我五花大綁帶到沙漠里
I'm talking he had me hog-tied in the desert
拿槍頂著我腦袋
with a gun to my head.
當著我的面折了兩個家伙的腿
Broke two guys' legs right in front of me.
要是我沒說服他  他可能就把他們...
If I hadn't talked him down, he probably would've...
血淋淋的細節就不談了  總之很慘
I'll spare you the gory details, but it was a deal and a half --
讓人永生難忘啊
not something you forget.
你跟我說這些干嘛
And you're telling me this why?
別太苛責自己
Don't be too tough on yourself.
人們說  謹慎即大勇
Like they say, discretion is the better part of valor.
換我也會這樣做
I would've done the same thing.
今天算我幫你  不收費
Hey, today, ‭it's on me -- no charge.
你搭下趟電梯
You take the next one.
照常收費
And bill me.
忘恩負義
Ingrate.
喂  吉米
Hey, Jimmy.
你跟霍華德說了嗎
Did you tell Howard yet?
我現在還不能說
I can't really talk right now.
你沒跟他說啊
You didn't tell him.
還沒  等確定了我才能說
No, and I won't until it's rock-solid,
要等到錄用通知書到手
like offer-letter-in-hand solid.
你什么時候能拿到錄用通知書
When are you gonna get that offer letter?
下禮拜四吧
‭I'm guessing next Thursday,
跟合伙人面試過以后
After my interview with the partners.
-那只是走個流程吧  -差不多
- Yeah, but that's just a formality, right? ‭- Basically.
希望是
I hope.
到底給你開的什么條件
What's the offer you think?
我是說實質的
I mean, brass tacks.
比不上你在戴維斯梅因律所的
Well, it's not gonna be as much as your deal at Davis & Main,
但是兩年后可以成為合伙人
but they'll make me partner in two years,
而在HHM需要五年或者永遠不能
as opposed to somewhere between five years and never at HHM.
不錯嘛
Not too shabby.
還幫我還法學院貸款
Yeah, and then there's my law-school loans.
還要還多少  幾千塊嗎
What is that -- a couple grand by now?
只有幾千就好了
I wish.
我還有其他開支
I had to finance the whole thing
當時還拿的是收發室工資
and was only making mailroom money.
還剩一萬五沒有還完
I've got ‭like $15,000 left.
斯韋卡特還真是想挖你啊
Schweikart wants you bad, huh?
但是  吉米
But, J -- but, Jimmy,
你找我有什么事
Did you have something you needed?
不不  就打電話問問
No, no. I was just checking in.
一會兒見  好嗎
Uh, I'll see you later, okay?
如果你表現好的話
If you play your cards right.
拜拜
Bye.
奧馬爾  你在哪
Omar, where are you?
奧馬爾  幫我寫封信行嗎
Omar, would you be so kind as to take a letter for me?
"最親愛的克利福德"  不  太過了
"Dearest Clifford..." No, that's too much.
"親愛的克利福"
"Dear Cliff..."
你覺得應該叫克利福德還是克里福
Whaddaya think -- Clifford or Cliff?
我不知道  要看是什么信吧
I don't -- it depends on what the letter is.
沒事  你看著寫吧
That's fine. Treat yourself.
親愛的  加什么都可以
Uh, "Dear..." Whoever you put in.
接下來  "我的心沉重得就像"
Continuing -- ‭uh, "My heart is heavy as --"
不行  聽起來像是身體出狀況了
No, that sounds like a medical condition.
這么寫吧
Let's go with, um,
"我懷著沉重的心情"  好吧
"It is with a heavy heart," Okay?
"我懷著沉重的心情向戴維斯梅因律所
"It is with a heavy heart that I tender my resignation
"正式提交辭呈"
"to Davis & Main."
用"提交"比"上交"好吧
"Tender" is better than "Submit," Yeah?
你說辭呈嗎
Resignation?
是啊
Yes, sir.
"向戴維斯梅因律所提交...
So, "Tender," Blah, blah, blah, "To Davis & Main.
"在這里工作的日子
"These have been, uh,
"是我一生中最有職業成就感的一段時間"
"some of the most professionally satisfying days of my life..."
怎么了
What's wrong?
是不是說得有點過了
Do you think ‭I'm laying it on too thick?
不是...
No, um...
我只是沒想到你在這里這么受氣
I just didn't realize how unhappy you were here.
不是受氣
Not unhappy, per se.
而是...不開心
More like... Not happy.
我完全沒看出來
I had no idea.
不是你的錯  伙計
‭It's not your fault, buddy.
你很能干
It's just -- you're top-notch.
我們寫到哪了
Where were we?
可是你那么努力才爭取到這一切
It's just y-you worked so hard to get here,
現在放棄的話你會失去很多
and it's so much to give up --
單說你的特別待遇
I-I mean, the perks alone.
是啊
Yeah.
公寓確實...不錯
The apartment is, uh... Yeah.
還有車
And the car.
那輛車整體上是相當不錯的
For the most part, car is pretty sweet.
還有簽約獎金
And the bonus.
獎金已經到手了
The bonus is a done deal.
他們早就把支票給我了
It's -- ‭they already cut me the check.
獎金我可以留著
I get to keep the bonus.
除非你辭職
Not if you quit.
在一定時間內辭職  我記得你的是一年內
Before a certain term -- I think yours is a year --
你就要把錢還回來的
You have to pay the money back.
是...
It's, um...
這個...
Yeah, uh, um...
對  就是這里...
Uh, uh, yeah, it's, uh...
應該是這兒
I think it's right, uh, there.
我看看
Yeah.
奧馬爾  這個
Omar...That whole, ‭uh,
辭職信的事情
letter-of-resignation thing
我不是認真的  一個字也不作數
that -- I didn't mean that, not a word.
我...
I...
我只是
I-I'm so incredibly
壓力太大了
stressed out.
壓力太大
I'm stressed out.
而且  坦白說
And frank-- to be honest,
適應戴維斯梅因的工作節奏
it has been more of an adjustment
比我預想中更困難
than I expected here at Davis & Main.
所以我有點  別把我剛才說的告訴別人
And so I just -- don't repeat what I said to anyone.
我就覺得有些不對勁
I figured ‭something had to be wrong --
肯定不對勁  因為你很喜歡在這里工作吧
I mean, really wrong because you like it here, right?
愛死了
I love it.
剛剛  就當是一瞬間失去理智吧
It -- call it ?A momentary lapse of reason.
我們
And but just --
我們忘了這回事吧
Let's just rewind the tape and, you know, forget this happened.
沒問題  絕對不說出去
Mum's the word. No problem.
我感覺好多了
Yeah, I feel better already.
有時候必須把想說的大聲發泄出來
I -- you know, sometimes, you have to say something out loud
才知道那聽起來有多荒唐
to hear how crazy it sounds.
謝謝你  奧馬爾
Thank you, Omar.
阿爾布開克  二十六英里
吉米·麥吉爾
Jimmy Mcgill.
吉米  這位是聯盟殯儀館的艾爾·紐曼
Jimmy, this is Al Newman of Allied Funeral Homes.
很高興見到你  艾爾
Great to meet you, Al.
-領帶不錯  -謝謝
- Nice tie. ‭- Thanks.
好了
All right.
我們開始吧
Let's get started, shall we?
你在干什么
What are you doing?
道格  給辦公室弄了臺榨汁器
Hey, Doug! ‭Got a juicer for the office!
吉米  太吵了
Jimmy, it's very loud!
-布萊恩  進來  -我們的委托人在外面
- Brian, come on in! - We have clients out there!
-好的  兩杯  馬上  -吉米
- Sure, you can! Two coming right up! - Jimmy --
有時候塞太多會堵住
Sometimes, it gets a little jammed.
你得用力才行  像這樣
You just got to force it. Yeah!
天哪
Oh, shit!
該死  濺得到處都是
Shi-- I'm -- I'm spreading it around.
-濺到你身上了嗎  -沒有
- Did I get you? ‭- Nah.
現在弄上了
I -- oh, ‭now I got you with this.
天哪  吉米
For Christ's sakes, Jimmy!
只能倒著來  明白嗎
Backwards only -- solo backward-o, yeah?
因為這樣才有吸力  杠桿原理啥的
Because, uh, you've got suction that way, leverage.
這是物理  物理
It's physics -- el physico!
克利福德先生希望地板干干凈凈
Oh, Don Clifford wants his floors clean --
清潔干凈
limpio, limpiar.
明白嗎[以上對話夾雜西語]
Uh. Comprende?
老兄  我是密歇根人
Dude, I'm from Michigan.
所以我剛才說的你一個字都聽不懂
So you don't understand a word I've been saying.
那好吧
Well...
晚安
Good night.
來  你試一下  倒著吸
No, you try. Backwards.
不好意思
Excuse me.
請大家注意一下
Can I have everyone's attention, please?
都能聽見嗎  很好
Everyone can hear me? Good.
坦白說  我從沒想到
Frankly, this is not a conversation
在自己的職業生涯中要進行這種講話
I ever thought I would have in my professional career,
但我注意到
but it's been brought to my attention
洗手間出了狀況
that we have an ongoing situation in the washroom.
有人上完不沖水
Someone is not flushing.
一次是意外  兩次也是
Once is an accident -- maybe even twice.
三次就形成模式了
Three times -- no, that's a pattern.
而且還不是小便
And we're not talking about a number one.
是的  謝謝你  艾琳
Yes. Thank you, Erin.
我不是來給誰難堪的
Now, I'm not here to shame anyone --
我都不想知道是誰干的  但是...
Nor do I even want to know who did it, but --
克利福德  是我干的
Uh, Cliff, it was me.
吉米  我說了我不想知道
Jimmy, I just said I didn't want to know.
我們需要節約水
Hey, we need the water.
我聽說圣達菲的水位
I read somewhere that the Santa Fe watershed
今年下降了五厘米
is down ‭two full inches this year.
每沖一次水
Every time you flush a toilet,
都會浪費一加侖水  一加侖呢
you waste a gallon of water -- a gallon!
還有比不沖水更好的節約方法嗎
What could be greater than this?
那些都是低流馬桶  吉米
They're low-flow toilets, Jimmy.
從現在開始  你要沖水
From now on, flush.
低流  不錯啊
Low-flow -- that's good.
好主意
Good thinking.
什么聲音
What is that?
吉米  里面怎么回事
Jimmy, ‭what's goin' on in there?
吉米
Jimmy!
你隔著門也能聽見嗎
Oh, you could hear this through the door?
我沒注意到  抱歉
I didn't realize. I'm sorry.
你在干什么
What do you think you're doing?
我接受了你的建議
Uh, I took your advice.
我在釋放壓力
I'm blowing off steam.
釋放壓力
Blowing off steam?
是啊  就像你彈吉他一樣
Yeah, yeah, like you and your guitar, you know?
不得不說  你說得沒錯
Um, I got to say -- you're right.
這非常有助于緩解壓力
I mean, ‭it really helps with stress.
聲音不怎么好聽  但我剛學
I know I don't sound very good, but I'm just learning.
我聽說關鍵是要一直讓這個氣囊充氣
I heard that the key is you have to keep this bag inflated.
夠了
Enough!
趕緊給我放下來
Put that down. Now.
你來我辦公室一趟
I want you in my office.
你贏了
You win.
我贏了什么
What do I win?
你被炒了
You're fired.
什么  克利福德  如果是因為那個風笛...
What? Cliff, if this is about the bagpipes --
不是因為那個風笛
It's not about the bagpipes.
當然是因為風笛了
Well, of course it's the bagpipes.
是因為風笛  是因為不沖水
It's the bagpipes, ‭and it's the not flushing
還因為你這身...扎眼的所謂西裝
And this -- this optical migraine you call a business suit.
是因為...是因為你想保住你的獎金
It's about -- it's about you keeping your bonus.
都是因為這個
That's what this is about.
你最近一直在溫習合同法吧
Been brushing up on ‭your contract law, haven't you?
你顯然想離開這里
You want outta here, clearly,
但你不能辭職  否則獎金不保
But you can't just up and quit and expect to keep your bonus.
如果我因為你的不當行為解雇你
And if I fire you for cause --
在你拍廣告時我就應該炒了你...
Like I should have done for the TV commercial --
獎金也沒有
Again, no bonus.
但是
However,
如果無緣無故  就因為你是個混蛋而解雇你
if I fire you not for cause but for being an all-around jackass...
你就能得逞了
Yeah.. ‭Hurray for you.
如果你認為我有什么瀆職行為...
If you think there's been some malfeasance here --
省省吧
Oh, save it.
我可以和你爭  但我不想為你浪費時間
I could fight you on this, but you're not worth my time.
你最好趕緊走人
I'd rather just have you gone.
你這么想我很抱歉
I'm sorry you feel that way.
我去...收拾東西
I'll just, uh... pack up.
首先...行行好
First... Do me the favor
不要把我當傻子
of not treating me like a fool for once.
告訴我  我到底對你哪里不好了
Tell me -- ‭how exactly did I mistreat you?
我到底做了什么讓你這樣對我
What did I do to deserve is kind of behavior?
我們給了你機會  鼓勵你發展
We gave you opportunities, encouraged you to excel.
給你配了車  配了房
We got you a car, an apartment.
還有黃檀木辦公桌
Hell, that cocobolo desk.
你在這兒看到過那樣的桌子嗎
Do you see a desk like that in here?
你根本沒有認真考慮
You never gave this a chance.
為什么
Why?
我努力想要適應  真的
I tried to make it work -- really, I-I did.
我只是...不適合這里
I'm just... a square peg.
如果你早就知道  為什么還要接受這份工作
If you knew that, why did you take the job?
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
那張桌子多少錢
How much was the desk?
七千
$7,000.
我會給你開張支票
I'll write you a check.
隨便  雖然不知道有什么用
Fine, ‭for whatever good that does.
帶上你的桌子離開這里
Take your desk and get out.
克利福德  不管怎么樣  我覺得你是一個好人
Hey, Cliff, for what it's worth, I think you're a good guy.
不管怎么樣  我覺得你是一個混蛋
For what it's worth, I think you're an asshole.
哈姆林先生
抱歉通知你  我將辭去
門開著
Uh, yeah, it's open.
-吉米  -我能和你談談嗎
- Jimmy. ‭- Hey. Can I talk to you for a minute?
霍華德知道你來嗎
Does Howard know you're here?
當然不知道  我溜進來的
God, no. I snuck in.
好吧  但是快點
Well, uh, yeah, but make it quick.
其實  我們能不能去會議室談
Actually, can we, uh, talk in the conference room?
為什么
Why?
這樣更正式
It's just more appropriate.
四點之前沒人要開會  我看過了
Um, no one's gonna need it till 4:00 -- I checked.
行嗎
Please?
最多十分鐘
10 minutes, tops.
你先請
After you.
坐吧
‭Have a seat.
怎么...怎么回事
What -- what is going on?
說吧
Spill it.
好吧
Okay.
斯韋卡特考科利會幫你付清欠哈姆林麥吉爾的債務
Schweikart and Cokely will pay your debt to HHM
并在兩年之后將你提拔為合伙人吧
and make you a partner in two years, correct?
顯然是的
Apparently.
是這么約定的
That's the deal, yes.
怎么了
Why?
要不要考慮一個更好的工作機會
Would you entertain a better offer?
誰給的  哈姆林麥吉爾聯合律所嗎
From whom -- HHM?
我
From me.
我明天就讓你成為合伙人
I'll make you a partner tomorrow.
以此為證
Consider that proof of concept --
韋克斯勒麥吉爾合伙律所
Wexler-Mcgill, partners at law.
你和我一起
You and me, together.
斯韋卡特可以幫你償還債務  我也可以
If Schweikart can pay your debt, so can I.
再加上我的簽約獎金
And with my signing bonus,
你就可以從頭開始了
you'll have a clean slate.
前程無限好
The sky's the limit.
我倆合作很好的
Hey, we're good together.
這你知道的
You know that.
還猶豫什么
So, what's stopping us?
全身心投入  做自己的老板
Let's jump in with both feet, be our own bosses,
共建屬于我們的未來
build our own future.
"做自己的老板"
"Be our own bosses."
哪里來的委托人呢
What about clients?
你剛剛簽了梅薩維德銀行  是吧
Mesa Verde just signed with you, didn't they?
想把他們挖走很難
It'll be a hard sell to take them with me.
那就再找一個梅薩維德銀行
So, then there will be another Mesa Verde.
這全都靠你  金
That was all you, Kim.
你能簽下這個  再簽一個有何難
You did it once. You can do it again.
你說得輕松
You make it sound easy.
不  你面前的這個男人
No. You're talking to a guy
可是在美甲店里蝸居了多年的
who lived ‭in the back of a nail salon.
當然不容易  肯定要付出很多心血和汗水
No, this is gonna be a whole lot of blood, sweat, and tears --
至少一開始肯定很艱難
at least, at the start.
但是最終我們會擁有完全屬于我們的生意
But in the end, we'll have a practice that is 100% ours,
很值得
that's worth it.
也有可能失敗  兩手空空
Or we fail ‭and end up with nothing.
你說得對  這就是一場賭博
Well, you're right -- it's a gamble.
這是一場豪賭
It's a big one.
沒錯  但你是把賭注壓在自己身上
Yeah, ‭but you're betting on yourself,
就我看來  你贏的幾率很大
and from where I sit, the odds are in your favor.
你是一名出色的律師
You're an amazing lawyer.
這是你向世界展示的機會
This is your chance to show the world that.
那我為什么不去斯韋卡特呢
So, why not go to Schweikart?
他們也會讓我成為合伙人
They'll make me partner,
而且他們律所可靠  聲譽又好
and they are a solid, respectable firm.
這一點無可否認
You can't deny that.
你不該只滿足于這樣的橫向調動
You deserve more than just a lateral move.
這就是斯韋卡特代表的
Bottom line -- that's what Schweikart represents.
他只是另一個霍華德·哈姆林罷了
He's just Howard Hamlin by a different name.
你一直在說我和斯韋卡特
You keep talking about me and Schweikart.
那你和戴維斯梅因怎么辦
What about you and Davis & Main?
結束了  我今天辭職了
That's over. I quit today.
嚴格來講  是我被炒了
Well, technically, I got fired.
怎么了
What happened?
互相看不順眼  而且由來已久
It was mutual and a long time coming.
這份工作從一開始就不適合我
That job was never the right fit for me.
這份才是
This is.
如果我們倆要成為律所合伙人
If we're gonna be law partners,
有一件事我需要確認
I need to know one thing.
你會是什么樣的律師
What kind of lawyer are you gonna be?
我不是指你要專攻哪一方面  我指的是
I don't mean what kind of law are you gonna practice. I mean
你會照章辦事嗎
are you gonna play it straight,
還是繼續
or are you gonna...
耍各種花招
be colorful?
我會照章辦事  絕不出格
I'm gonna play it straight, right down the line.
我會萬分謹慎
I'm gonna dot every "I," and I'm gonna cross every...
如果我不能做自己  那這又有什么意義
There's no point in me doing this if I can't be myself.
每一次我照著別人的方法來做事
Every time I try to do things someone else's way,
我都會把事情搞砸
it blows up in my face.
在戴維斯梅因律所就是如此
That's what happened at Davis & Main.
看看結果如何
Look how that turned out.
我差點毀了你的事業  惹毛了所有人
I almost derailed your career, pissed everyone off.
我一直都努力活在別人的期望中
I've been trying to be the person someone else wants me to be for...
我也不知道有多久了
I don't know how long.
一開始是查克
I mean, first, it was Chuck,
然后是你  這并不是你的錯
then it was you -- ‭and that's not your fault.
那是我自己的選擇
That was my choice.
但是如果我們要這么做
But if we're gonna do this,
我要做我自己
I got to go into it as me.
所以  沒錯
So, yeah.
我估計會繼續耍小花招吧
Colorful, I guess.
你覺得怎么樣
What do you say?
我只是
I just...
我不明白為什么我倆非要在一起工作呢
I don't see ‭why it's so important to you that we work together.
我們已經...
I mean, we're already...
你為什么還要拉我入伙呢
‭Why do you need me for this?
我不是需要你  我想要你
I don't need you -- I want you.
你已經擁有我了...
You've got me...
只不過不是合伙人
Just not as a law partner.
我得回去工作了
I have to get back to work.
你沒事吧
You okay?
沒事
Yeah.
沒事  我很好
No, I'm fine.
去吧
Go on.
那一會見
See you later? ‭
一會見
Yeah.
你也看到了  這房子可以拎包入住
It's move-in ready, as you can see.
在過去三年里已經重新裝修過了
And they've renovated within the past three years --
地板和廚房都是新的
new floors, new kitchen.
空間也很大
And it's a good amount of space.
你覺得這房子不算太過吧
It's not too much house, you think?
一點也不過分
No, not at all.
看看那后院啊
And look at that backyard.
他們把小房子都留在這了
They're leaving the playhouse.
是不是很棒
Isn't that amazing? ‭
凱莉肯定愛死了
Kaylee will go crazy for that.
-她肯定進去了就不想出來  -是吧
- You'll never get her outta there. - I know, right?
最重要的是
And the most important part --
周圍的學校很不錯  鄰居也很棒
the schools are good and the neighborhood is great.
我打了本警區的電話  問了犯罪率
I called the local precinct and asked about the crime stats --
這里是市里最低的之一
they're some of the lowest in the city.
而且  他的語氣很好
Plus, I got a good vibe from him.
聽起來很負責任
Like, they sounded really responsive.
這很不錯
That sounds perfect.
是的
Yeah.
你喜歡嗎
Do you like it?
你開心我就開心
If you're happy, I'm happy.
你喜歡嗎
Do you like it?
是  我喜歡  但是我
Yeah, I do, but I'm --
-但是什么  -需要一大筆錢
- But what? - ‭It's a lot of money.
我知道我一直重復  但確實要很多錢
I know -- I'm like ‭a broken record, but it is.
這你不必擔心
You don't worry about that.
無論多少錢都要買下來
We'll make it happen, whatever the cost.
-麥克  -我說真的
- Mike. - ‭Hey, I'm serious.
別多想了
Not another thought.
你想要就買吧
If you want it, it's yours.
房子怎么樣
How we looking?
非常棒
Oh, it's perfect.
-成交  -非常好
- Let's do it. ‭- Fantastic.
你們還有時間嗎
Do you have another hour?
我們可以去辦公室
We could go down to the office,
申請貸款預批之類的
get the pre-approval in order, all that.
可以  我們在那兒見
Oh, sounds good. We'll meet you there.
行  一會兒見
Sure. See you in a few.
我終于能松口氣了
Oh, I feel like I can finally breathe.
行  我很高興
Good. I'm glad.
你想坐我的車嗎
You wanna ride together?
不  我跟著你開
No, I'll follow you over.
車不錯
Car looks good.
連剮蹭的痕跡都看不出來
Wouldn't even know ‭you so much as scratched it.
沒錯  修車工技術好
Yeah, um, my guy knows his stuff.
爸  謝謝你做的一切
Thank you, pop, for everything.
開車去吧
You go on now.
-我們在那兒見  -行
- I'll see you there. - ‭'kay.
抱歉  剛才紅綠燈差點把你弄丟了
Sorry I almost lost you at that light.
沒事
No problem.
小心魚缸
Watch the fish tank.
左邊
To the left.
我左邊  我左邊
My left, my left.
好了
There.
你覺得如何
What do you think?
行
Uh, yeah.
還挺...
It's, um...
還行
Yeah.
這東西要怎么處理
‭What should I... do with this?
丟到路邊去
Dump it ‭on the side of the road --
我當初也是在路邊撿的
That's where I got it in the first place.
-給  伙計  -不用
- Hey, buddy. - ‭Oh, no.
-你幫我太多了  去喝一杯呢  -真的沒關系
- This is over and above. ‭How about a drink?‬ - That's okay, really.
-我想喝一杯  -不用了
- I know I could use one. - ‭No.
來吧  我請客
Come on. I'm buying.
我真不用  開長途車
No, I'm good. Long drive.
喝些黃瓜水再上路
Cucumber water for the road?
沒事的  謝謝
I'm -- I'm totally set. Thank you.
我得回家照顧孩子
Gotta get home to my kids.
那你呢
How about you?
你現在準備怎么辦
What are you gonna do now?
勇往直前
Onward and upward.
謝謝  奧馬爾
Thanks, Omar.
一路平安
Drive safe.
你好
Hello!
這里是詹姆斯·M·麥吉爾先生的律所
You've reached the law offices of James M. McGill, esquire.
請留...
Kindly leave...
你好
Hi.
這里是吉米·麥吉爾的律所
You've reached the law offices of Jimmy McGill.
請留言
Please leave a message,
我會盡快回復
and I'll get back to you as soon as I can.
謝謝
Thanks.
簡易判決嗎  是的  我處理過六起
Summary judgments? Uh, yes. I've handled six.
其實最近一起非常復雜
Actually, one recently was quite complex.
一起訴訟案  離婚不順造成的
It was a litigation -- the result of a nasty divorce.
我的委托人起訴她以前的公司
My client was suing her former company,
她和前夫在協議書中分了該公司的財產
which she and her ex had split in their settlement.
其中的問題讓我研究了幾周判例法
The issues involved had me chasing case law for weeks.
-誰審理的  -皮特曼法官
- Who heard it? ‭- Judge Pittman.
他很難纏啊
That guy -- he's a handful, huh?
他有時候是很難搞
Well, he can be a tough nut to crack,
但他做出了有利于我的判決
but he did rule in my favor.
行了  別總說法律了
All right, ‭enough about law, law, law.
我們知道你很棒
We know you're good.
我們知道你很懂行
We know you know your stuff.
說說金·韋克斯勒
Tell us about Kim Wexler.
你從收發室干起
You started in the mailroom.
-是吧  -沒錯
- Is that right? - ‭I did.
這大概是十年前的事了
I was there almost, ‭uh, well, 10 years ago now.
一步一步往上爬  很不錯
Pulled yourself up by your bootstraps -- I like that.
你上過新墨西哥大學法學院  你是新墨西哥人嗎
I see you went to UNM law. Are you from New Mexico?
老家不在這
Not originally.
我是中西部人
I'm from the Midwest,
地圖上都沒有的小鎮
Just a tiny, little town barely on the map --
堪薩斯和內布拉斯加交界處
You know, ‭that Kansas-Nebraska border.
你們肯定沒聽過
You've never heard of it.
那你怎么到這兒來了
So, what brought you here?
也許...
I guess...
有一天  我回顧人生  回顧曾經的我
Uh, one day, ‭I just looked around at my life, at who I was,
我意識到  如果繼續走那條路的話
and realized if I kept going the way I was going...
哪條路
Which way was that?
最好的情況
Best case?
可能是嫁給鎮上開加油站的那個人
Probably married to the guy that ran the town gas station.
也可能是在辛奇丁奇當個收銀員
Maybe cashiering down at the Hinky Dinky.
-辛奇什么  -辛奇丁奇
- The Hinky what? - ‭Hinky Dinky.
我們那兒的超市
It was our supermarket.
我只是想要其他的東西
‭I just wanted something else.
你想要什么
What did you want?
更多
More.
感謝前來  和你聊天真高興
Well, thanks for coming by. Always a pleasure.
總算見到本人了
Great to put a face to the name.
-謝謝  -我們要一起討論一下
- Oh, thanks. - ‭We are gonna put our heads together and discuss,
但我可以保證
but I feel safe to say that you can expect
最晚明天就能給你消息
to hear from us by tomorrow at the latest.
那真是太棒了
That's... fantastic.
我很期待
I look forward to it.
你一走進來  我們就喜歡上你了
We liked you when you came in here.
現在更喜歡你了
We like you more now.
感謝你們抽出時間
Well, thank you so much for taking the time,
稍后再聊吧
and I will, uh, ‭speak to you soon.
認識你真高興  琳恩
It was great to meet you, Lynne.
-我也是  -再見  派瑞
- You, too. - ‭Perry.
幸會  金
‭Pleasure, Kim.
-霍華德  -其實我是里奇
- Howard. - It's Rich, actually.
天啊  真是太抱歉了
Oh, my god. I'm so sorry.
不用  我很高興你把我和霍華德弄混了
No, no, no, no. I'm happy to be confused with Howard.
他實在太帥了  別放在心上
He's a damn good-looking man. Don't worry about it.
來吧  我送你出去吧
Uh, come on. I'll walk you out.
你好  我想見吉米
Hi. I'm, uh, here to see Jimmy.
他正在開會
He's in a meeting.
-開會  -請坐
- A meeting? - ‭Have a seat.
聽好
And, listen --
我不想再聽到"許可證"這個詞
I don't ever want to hear the word "Permit" again.
明白嗎
Capisce?
你會遭報應的  哥們
It's your funeral, dude.
你在這兒干什么
What are you doing here?
正好來附近
Just in the neighborhood.
好
Great.
這次我想要臺移動攝影車
Oh, and I want a dolly this time.
均為移動攝影車品牌
哪種  "西方"  "騙子"  "小家伙"
What kind? Western? Hustler? Pee-wee?
在女士面前注意措辭
Hey, watch your mouth around the lady.
我哪知道
How the hell should I know?
你才懂啊  便宜點就行
You're the nerd. Just make it cheap.
快去吧
Now, go on. Get outta here.
我看到你把舊車弄回來了
I see you got your old car back.
是啊
Yeah.
捐都捐不出去
The kidney people wouldn't take it.
抱歉
Sorry. ‭
你終于有張黃檀木辦公桌了
Well, you finally got your cocobolo desk.
我終于有張黃檀木辦公桌了
‭Finally got my cocobolo desk.
這是個好兆頭
Feel like it's a good omen for what's next.
什么好事
And what's that?
就這個
This.
個體律所  又一次給自己打工
Solo practice, being my own man again.
和斯韋卡特的見面怎么樣
So, how'd it go with Schweikart?
挺順利的
Uh, went well.
明天就能拿到錄用通知書了
Should be getting their offer tomorrow.
真不錯
That's fantastic.
我真為你高興
I'm really happy for you.
謝謝
Thanks.
我們應該慶祝
You know what? We should celebrate.
吃漢堡吧  我請客
Whataburger -- on me.
我不會接受那份工作
I'm not taking the job.
為什么
Why not?
你說得對  我應該做自己的老板了
You were right -- it's time for me to be my own boss.
個體律所
Solo practice.
怎么  你又覺得這么做不好了
‭What? You don't think it's a good idea now?
別告訴我你改變主意了
Don't tell me ‭you've changed your mind.
不  我很驚訝而已
No, ‭I'm -- I'm surprised, is all.
我一直都說
Hey, I s-- I said all along,
你太優秀  那幫鄉巴佬不配
you're too good for those clowns.
這實在是...
I mean, this is, uh...
棒極了
Shit, yeah. Wow!
太棒了
It's great.
好
Good.
為此  我有個提議
To that end... I have a pitch for you.
不是韋克斯勒麥吉爾  而是韋克斯勒
Not Wexler-McGill, but Wexler...
以及麥吉爾
and McGill.
我們找間辦公室  平攤物業費
We find an office, ‭share the housekeeping costs,
房租  電費  一切
the rent, electricity -- everything.
但我是律師金·韋克斯勒
But I am Kim Wexler, attorney at law,
你是律師吉米·麥吉爾
and you are Jimmy McGill, attorney at law,
我們都可以按自己意愿執業
both free to practice as we see fit.
同一屋檐下兩間律所
Separate firms under one roof?
我們都要出城  為什么不拼車呢
We're both headed uptown, so why can't we share a taxi?
你按你的方式來  我按我的來
You do things your way, and I do them mine.
我們有自由
We'll have freedom,
但也不會孤軍奮戰
but we aren't each trying to go it alone.
不是合伙人  而是一起工作的個體律師
Not partners -- ‭solo practitioners, together.
你覺得怎么樣
What do you think?
我不知道說什么好
I don't know what to say.
說同意吧
Say yes.
人人留學——開啟單向收費新時代
英、澳、日三國免費辦理
眾多美國大學，快捷錄取
人人留學【免費辦理】
震撼上線，趕快登陸
www.rrliuxue.com